Framing Britney Spears is a documentary film directed by Samantha Stark.
Her rise was a global phenomenon.
Her downfall was a cruel national sport.
People close to Britney Spears and lawyers tied to her conservatorship now reassess her
career as she battles her father in court over who should control her life.
Self (archive footage), played by Britney Spears.
The New York Times Presents: Framing Britney Spears is a 2021 American documentary film directed by Samantha Stark, reported and produced
by Liz Day, and produced by Liz Hodes, Mary Robertson, Jason Stallman, Sam Dolnick, Ken Druckerman and Stephanie Preiss.
The documentary follows the life and career of American singer Britney Spears, her rise to fame as a global music superstar at age 16, her gratuitous and misogynistic treatment by the media and paparazzi, her highly
publicized breakdown in 2007, the conservatorship that between 2008 and 2021 placed her involuntarily under the control of her father Jamie Spears, and the #FreeBritney movement sparked by Spears's fanbase.
The documentary was released on February 5, 2021 as an edition of
The New York Times Presents on FX and FX on Hulu.
Shortly after the documentary aired, a probate judge dismissed objections
by Jamie regarding the co-conservatorship arrangement.
The documentary garnered critical acclaim, and widespread international media coverage, contributing to heightened mainstream
public awareness of the conservatorship dispute and a reassessment of Spears' sexist and gratuitous treatment.
The documentary won the TCA Award for Outstanding Achievement in News and Information, and received two nominations at
the 73rd Primetime Creative Arts Emmy Awards, including for Outstanding Documentary or Nonfiction Special.
The film explores themes of pop star, paparazzi, civil
rights, mental breakdown, biography.